[The Heir]
[Episode 18]
[Entry Permit
for the Tribute Ink Selection]
His Majesty
has moved up the Tribute Ink selection.
Looking across Huizhou,
the Tian family is stuck in lawsuits,
while the Chen family
hasn't launched anything new
except the Scholar Ink.
Driven by stress, Lord Yan
came to us and tried
to reconcile us and Zhen.
Today,
we rejected his kindness.
We should pay a visit to him
someday
and apologize in person.
The problem is
how we express our apologies.
Are we going to bring Li Zhen along?
If so, before that happens,
should we also hold
a grand ceremony
to welcome the Eighth Branch back?
Well said.
Lord Yan obviously looks down
on the Li family
and thinks everyone of us as incompetent.
For insisting that we must attend
the Tribute Ink selection with that girl,
he's such a foolish eunuch.
In my opinion, it is he
who owes an apology
to the Sixth Uncle and the Third Brother.
Enough.
If this gets out,
where will the Li family stand?
You must refrain
from saying such words again.
Do you hear me?
Yes, Sister-in-law.
As a matter of fact,
Lord Yan took that action
because he holds the Li family
in high regard.
He holds us in high regard?
Does that mean he has to attach
the Eighth Branch to us?
Sister-in-law,
you also think that we should
have Zhen back for the selection,
don't you?
Didn't Zhen already make it clear?
She refuses to come back.
As someone expelled from the clan,
is she even entitled to refuse anything?
Sister-in-law,
do you mean
that if Zhen agrees,
we should admit her back into the clan?
Is it what you're suggesting?
Shut up!
Are you out of your mind, huh?
The Li family
has declined to such a state.
If there were full of talents
and excellent ink products
like before,
would Lord Yan
have said those words today?
Father, are you saying
that even you don't think
I'm able to create the new Yunsong Ink?
None of you have faith in me, do you?
Nobody in this family believes in me,
right?
Jingdong!
You...
Father.
Aunt Rujun.
Over the past few months,
Jingdong has spent days and nights
in the ink workshop.
He would even sacrifice his soul
to the new Yunsong Ink if it could help.
I believe we will surely
be granted the privilege
to produce the Tribute Ink
if we send Jingdong's creation
to the selection.
Halt!
Sit down.
This is my fault.
This is all my fault.
I fought Jinshui for nearly
the entirety of my life.
I also forced Jingdong
to compete with Jingqi
and Jingfu
when he was little.
The Tribute Ink case years ago
took Jingqi's life.
Jingfu
died outside
and couldn't even be buried
in the ancestral grave.
Jinshui was expelled from the clan.
He even swore an oath
to never make ink anymore.
There's no one left
for me and my son to fight against.
Given that,
we've been tormenting each other.
You, Jingdong, are always
harboring resentment
and antagonizing others.
As for your wife,
she is cautious in every way,
trying to protect and pamper you
out of fear of more damage to your legs,
which will break your heart again.
And your son...
Every day, he is busy doing
heaven knows what
and never steps into the ink workshop.
Look what has become
of a perfectly fine young man.
You're criticizing me.
Then what about you?
Apart from supervising production
in the ink workshop,
have you ever made
one single piece of new ink?
That aside, you even
picked a terrible man
for your daughter as her husband!
Aren't you ashamed when you reprimand me?
It's the father's fault
for not properly educating his son!
Jingdong!
You've gone way out of line.
Quick, come with me.
Old Madam,
Sixth Master,
something happened in the ink workshop!
Old Madam,
Sixth Master,
Manager Shao is taking
a group of ink-makers
to the ancestral hall
to petition for Miss Li Zhen.
Sixth Master.
Young Master.
What are you lot up to?
Sixth Master,
glad that you came.
Upon hearing about
the main family's discussion
on whether to let Miss Li Zhen return
for the Tribute Ink selection,
we decided to come and petition for her.
Sixth Master,
we wrongly blamed Miss Li Zhen
for the previous ink recipe incident.
We'd like to apologize to her in person.
That's right, Sixth Master.
The ancient lacquer-soot ink
recreated by Miss Li Zhen
has become a top seller in Li Ink.
And her creation of Fu Jin Ink
is deeply favored by Lord Yan.
Plus, the medicinal ink
is a legacy left by the Li ancestors.
It's only reasonable
to enter these two types of ink
into the Tribute Ink selection.
If Miss Li Zhen returns,
Li Ink will surely regain the privilege
to produce the Tribute Ink.
-Sixth Master,
-please let Miss Li Zhen back.
So none of you believe
the Sixth Branch then?
You don't think I, Li Jingdong, am
competent for the Tribute Ink selection,
do you?
Manager Shao.
Young Master,
I don't mean any of that.
We just want what's the best for Li Ink.
Jingdong,
don't be rude to Manager Shao.
Father,
as the manager of the ink workshop,
he's meddling
with the main family's affairs,
and has gathered
a large group of workers
to petition for Li Zhen.
Isn't he overstepping his boundaries?
I'm only voicing what we all have
in our hearts.
We're acting solely
in the best interests of the main family.
What main family?
The Eighth Branch?
Is Li Zhen your master now?
Sixth Master,
please be the judge here.
We are...
doing this in good faith.
The Tian family is troubled by lawsuits.
The Chen family can't offer
a top-tier ink product as of now.
This year,
Li Ink stands
the highest chance of winning.
Please let Miss Li Zhen come back
so as to reclaim
the authority over the Tribute Ink.
-Reclaim the authority!
Listen up, all of you.
Even without Li Zhen,
I, Li Jingdong, am
still able to regain the privilege
of producing the Tribute Ink.
Now, go back to your work.
Move!
We in the Sixth Branch are
incapable of sustaining the Li family.
My son is incapable
of managing Li Ink well.
I, Li Jinhe, am woefully incompetent.
I'm so incompetent.
Father, stop hitting him!
Or Jingfu will die!
If you must hit someone, hit me!
I volunteer...
to be removed...
from the family register.
Please.
Please save my father.
Please come out here.
Mother,
just because our names
were removed from the family register,
does that mean
we're no longer part of the Li family?
From today on,
forget about that home.
This is our home now.
Do you understand?
Yes.
I'll kill anyone
who dares to touch us!
The ritual is completed.
Sister,
did you ask me to come
talk about
the Tribute Ink selection?
Li Zhen has declined Lord Yan's invitation
to the selection.
This matter is now known
to everyone in Huizhou.
You are seeking cooperation
with both Li Ink
and the New Li Ink.
Her absence from the Tribute Ink selection
will inevitably
affect the military supplies procurement.
You should try to persuade her.
In recent years,
ink-making talents in Huizhou
have dwindled.
Other prefectures have been in charge
of the Tribute Ink production for years.
For nearly a year,
among all the new Hui Ink products,
only the ancient lacquer-soot ink
and the Nine-Treasure Ink
have stood out.
And both of them
are creations of Li Zhen.
Given that, you should understand
the importance
of her attending the selection.
Sister, I understand that.
However... it is I
who has been taking care
of our ink business in Huizhou.
Please don't worry, Sister.
I'm not doubting your ability.
The military supplies procurement
is just too significant an issue.
We are deeply indebted
to Marshal Qi and the general,
so naturally this heavy responsibility
should be ours.
No blunders
are allowed in this matter.
I know.
"I wonder if things will remain
the same after today."
It's a doubt about
whether joy will continue after today.
What is it now?
Something on your mind?
The poet did an even better job
writing the last sentence:
"Savor today's happiness while it lasts,
as what tomorrow brings
is not our concern."
It's truly difficult for ordinary people
to reach the famous poet
Mr. Tao's state of mind.
Look,
the weather is lovely today.
If you can't continue with the reading,
why not take Mr. Tao's advice
and have some tea
and pastries,
so as to savor today's joy while it lasts?
Stop beating around the bush.
Just say whatever on your mind.
I'm not trying to say anything.
I haven't visited the New Li Ink Workshop
since the renovation was done.
That's why I came see you.
Don't you have
anything else to say?
No, nothing.
You're right.
The weather is so lovely
today.
Staying indoors to read
would be a waste of beautiful scenery.
Do you have time today?
Yes.
I'll take you somewhere then.
Let's go now.
Careful.
Whenever I feel distraught,
I would come here.
Every time I'm at this place,
I would feel much better.
Mr. Dongtu is unattached
to the mundane world,
while you, Zhen, are
a lady of her word.
I truly find you admirable.
I'm so flattered, Master Qi.
This is just the beginning.
Realizing Mr. Dongtu's dream
is by no means
an overnight effort.
Fine.
Then from today on,
count me in.
I know you came
meet me today just to talk me
into attending the Tribute Ink selection.
Over these few days,
everyone thinks I should attend
the Tribute Ink selection.
But they are unaware
that the Tribute Ink
is like a thorn in my side.
Every time I think of it,
all that comes to mind
is the whipping
my father was punished with,
the pouring rain
in which I knelt before the Li Residence
with my brother,
the tears my mother shedded
in front of my father's memorial tablet
without us knowing,
and my grandfather's hands,
stained dark by years of working with ink—
yet they could never touch ink again.
I hate to get involved
in the family power struggle.
I also hate to be a pawn
in the Tribute Ink battle.
I want to be away from those nightmares
as far as possible.
Do you know why I haven't
brought up the Tribute Ink today at all?
Because what I value...
is you,
Zhen.
This has nothing to do with you attending
the Tribute Ink selection or not.
Plus, as I'm looking at
this pinewood again today,
I'm feeling more assured
that even without
the authority over the Tribute Ink,
you, Li Zhen,
will definitely become Ming's
best ink maker one day.
Ming's
best ink maker?
I aspire
to become a much greater ink maker
than my grandfather.
I want everyone in Huizhou—
no—
everyone in Ming
to know my name, Li Zhen.
I believe you.
Your words
have reminded me of an old friend.
I guess it must be...
that
cowardly little boy, right?
Don't say that about my friend.
Fine, sure.
If he were still alive,
he would be
about your age now.
But he surely wouldn't be as tall as you.
Because you said he was only this big
last time.
Qi Jiu,
I never thought you'd come
for something other than to persuade me.
You are the first one
who isn't trying to talk me into attending
the Tribute Ink selection.
But I'm aware
that you came to Huizhou this time
exactly for the selection.
My decision might put you in a tough spot.
If you want to withdraw your investment
in the New Li Ink Workshop,
I'll have no complaints.
No, no.
I've always trusted my own judgment.
It's just
that I trust you even more right now.
So I definitely won't withdraw
my investment
in the New Li Ink Workshop.
Zhen,
just do whatever you want.
Then...
If the New Li Ink Workshop performs
better and better in the future,
I'll be glad to give you
an extra share of the benefits
as a reward for your trust in me today.
Good.
I'll be waiting to receive
dividends from you then, Zhen.
No problem.
This pinewood
is the witness to our pact.
Sure.
Come on,
dear guests,
this way, please.
Ronghua, I hope
this letter finds you well.
Autumn has just arrived.
How are you in the capital?
Everything is as usual in Huizhou.
The New Li Ink Workshop has started off
on the right track.
An adequate number of ink-makers
and workers have been hired.
This time,
I've even managed to recruit
a female worker.
The business is picking up.
Ronghua, will you
return to Huizhou
for this year's Mid-Autumn Festival?
If you will,
we must have a proper gathering.
Ronghua.
Mother.
Be seated.
I'm so sorry that Qi unluckily
passed away due to a sudden illness
before he could marry you.
Today, I'm here to ask you
about your plans for the future.
Mother,
although I couldn't become
your daughter-in-law for real,
you treat me as your own, and saved
the Tian family from grave trouble.
For that, I'm deeply grateful.
Mother, if you don't mind,
I'd love to be
a loyal companion to you forever,
paying respects morning and evening,
so as to repay your great kindness
by fulfilling filial duties
in the Young Master's stead.
Get up.
Sit down.
Ronghua,
you may call me Aunt from now on.
Yes, Aunt Wan.
I will keep that in mind.
Given your young age,
staying in the manor all day
will definitely bore you.
How about this?
In a few days,
I will take you to meet Sage Qing He.
He is now a noble royal preceptor.
If he agrees to let you stick around,
you'll get to see more of the world.
There you are, Hua'er.
Hua'er.
Zhen!
The New Li Ink Workshop's business
is really booming now.
Come sit down.
Here, be seated.
Zhen,
let me tell you some good news.
Starting today,
I will be working
in the New Li Ink Workshop.
Really?
Really.
Has the Seventh Grandmother agreed?
Yes. Not only that,
she also asked me to bring you something.
She said the freshly fermented
stinky mandarin fish inside
is your favorite, Zhen.
So she had me deliver it to you in person.
How considerate
of the Seventh Grandmother.
But why are there pine branches on top?
The Seventh Grandmother said
this is a Huizhou tradition.
It symbolizes
everlasting prosperity
and good luck.
So, I plucked some from the pine yard.
That was why I came a bit late.
Anything wrong?
What's wrong?
It's the fish head.
Just the fish head.
Zhen, you gave me such a fright.
I have so much more to say,
yet I can't speak it out now.
Alright.
My bad, Hua'er.
Go on. Go on with your talk.
Next, there's a message
from the Seventh Grandmother.
She said, "Little Zhen,
it's up to the Li family to decide
about the Tribute Ink selection.
After all, this is an obstacle
that the Li family must tackle
on their own.
It is in no way related to you.
Should they win or lose,
it won't concern you.
Little Zhen,
just try your best
to run the New Li Ink Workshop.
Also, congratulations
on creating Fu Jin Ink
and helping others out of hot water.
That makes you truly worthy of
being called upright and honorable."
I didn't say a single word wrong.
Many thanks to the Seventh Grandmother.
Hua'er,
where did you say
you got these pine branches?
The Li family's pine yard.
Anything wrong?
Come with me to the Li family's pine yard.
What for?
Mr. Zhao!
Bring a message to the Sixth Master
at Li Ink.
Tell him...
there might be a problem
with the Li family's pine yard.
Hua'er, hurry.
This way, Hua'er.
Do be careful.
As I speculated, it is
an outbreak of pine wilt disease.
The ink workshop has the pine yard
inspected once every half a month.
How did they fail to detect
this situation?
Pine wilt disease spreads very quickly.
It tends to occur in obscure locations.
Unless one happens to cut off
a pine tree's trunk in the early stages,
the condition can't be noticed.
However, now,
the illness has reached the top branches
and entered an incurable phase.
W-What should we do then?
Li Ink is known for its pine soot ink.
Now, with this outbreak
of pine wilt disease,
the production will inevitably decrease.
It'll also likely to affect
Li Ink's performance
in the Tribute Ink selection.
Hua'er!
Sixth Grandfather!
Sixth Grandfather.
Hua'er.
Zhen,
how are the pine trees?
Give me the knife!
-Sixth Grandfather!
No need to examine those.
I've just had a check over there!
Hold it.
Heaven has turned against us Li family.
Heaven has turned against us Li family!
Old Madam,
Eldest Young Lady.
Sixth Uncle.
It's true.
It's truly the pine wilt disease.
Jinhe,
now, will it be too late
to preserve the woods
by cutting down the infected trees?
If we had taken action
half a month earlier,
a patch of the woods might be protected.
But now, the disease
is spreading to every corner.
We can do nothing but wait for the trees
to recover on their own.
It will take at least three to five years.
The number could go up to as high as ten.
Manager Shao,
how much pine wood is left
in the ink workshop now?
Can it help us finish
all the existing orders?
Old Madam, we have exactly
500 cubic meters of pine wood.
If we use it sparingly,
it might last us for another two months.
Right now,
we have no choice but to pause
the development of new ink.
Pool all the pine wood together
to quickly produce ordered ink.
Send someone out of town
to look for new pine wood
to fill the future shortage.
Mother, are you
giving up
on the upcoming Tribute Ink selection?
Rujun,
the Li family has long been
without a foothold.
The Tribute Ink selection
is our only chance to turn things around.
Yes, Mother.
Jinhe,
the Tribute Ink selection is held
every few years.
Even if we bail on it this time,
we can still go for it another time.
However, if we stop
the supply of pine soot ink,
we'll suffer a loss
of ink buyers.
They will go find another supplier.
When that happens,
the Li family
will really become destitute!
Ever since ancient times,
survival has always been
prioritized over prosperity.
The Li family's business
has always centered on
pine soot ink for large orders.
If...
the foundation of our family business
is gone,
what else will be left for us?
[Ink Recipe]
Jingdong, it's time to eat.
Take it away. I'm not hungry.
Grab a few bites at least.
I'm telling you to take it away.
Father.
Jingdong,
eat some of it at least.
Don't let Ying's good intentions
go to waste.
Father,
the Tribute Ink selection will begin soon.
I'm running out of time.
We won't attend
the upcoming Tribute Ink selection.
Father,
what are you talking about?
I'm saying that we're quitting
the Tribute Ink selection.
Why?
There's an outbreak of pine wilt disease
in the pine yard.
Father,
even with that condition,
we can still go out to look for pine wood.
Why do we have to quit the selection?
Why must we give up, Father?
Father.
Father!
We must not bail on it.
Father,
do you know how much effort I've put
into this selection?
We can't just give up, Father.
Listen to me...
No, you listen to me, Father.
Do you remember what you told me
when I was a child?
You said that men should
always fight
and strive,
and that quitting is not an option.
Do you remember?
You said that the Eighth Branch
was not superior to us the Sixth Branch.
So I took your words.
I was more
hardworking and diligent
than Jingfu and Jingqi
when I was little.
I did it so that one day
everyone would come to realize
that I,
your son Li Jingdong, am
better than them both!
Just hear me out...
Father!
The Eighth Branch has been expelled.
Isn't this the best time
for us the Sixth Branch
to prove ourselves?
I will have everyone know
that I, Li Jingdong, am
the backbone of this family!
I am better than that little girl Li Zhen!
The Li family does have a competent heir.
Father,
I don't care what you do.
But I will by no means
back down!
[Champion of Ink Making]
My dear seventh and eighth brothers,
I'm sorry to be a disappointment
to you and the Li family.
I'm sorry.
Zhen, Zhen.
Why are you back so late today?
Mother, after much consideration
on the pine wilt disease,
I think I should tell Grandpa about it.
Anyway, Wuyuan isn't far away.
I plan to go pick Grandpa up
early tomorrow morning.
You're heading to Wuyuan tomorrow morning?
Yes.
Grandpa?
Father?
Why would you come back?
I got a message from Rujun.
The pine wilt disease outbreak
has to be handled at once.
I'm going to the Li Residence now.
B-Be careful then!
Jinshui.
Rujun.
Jinshui, why are you back?
Regarding the pine wilt disease,
Jinhe, Rujun,
what are your plans?
This outbreak could be said
as a lethal blow to Li Ink.
Perhaps Li Ink will have to
miss out
on the upcoming Tribute Ink selection.
Due to the pine wilt disease,
the best solution right now
is to withdraw from this selection.
Why, just because you said so?
Who are you to offer any advice
to the Li family?
Withdraw?
How could you even
bring yourself to suggest that?
Aunt Rujun,
outsiders can't share weal and woe
with Li Ink.
You know better than I do
about what kind of situation
the Li family has been reduced to today.
If we give up
on this Tribute Ink selection,
there will be no place
for Li Ink in Huizhou anymore.
Jingdong,
I understand you're fully dedicated
to Li Ink.
But now, given the pine wilt disease
and the importance of...
Not many people know about
the current condition yet.
We can even afford
century-old pine wood.
All we need to do is procure wood in time.
Even if we try to hide the truth,
how long can we keep it a secret?
Once the news gets out,
the price of pine wood will surely surge.
Merchants will hoard it
for a higher price.
If our delivery of goods is delayed,
that will be a disaster.
What disaster could be worse
than what happened years ago?
Li Jinshui,
to put it bluntly,
you
and the Eighth Branch
are the root cause of all disasters!
Jingdong!
Aunt Rujun,
I'm wholeheartedly fighting
for the best interests of Li Ink.
However,
you keep defending
this sinner of the Li family.
Fine.
Now that you all want to give up,
I, Li Jingdong, will set up
my own business.
Let's part ways
so you won't be bothered with me anymore!
You vile spawn!
What did you just say?
Say it again, I dare you!
Jinhe...
Jinshui, get up now.
I'm not strong enough to help you up.
Get up.
Rujun, Jinshui,
come on.
Take a look at this.
Is this the map of pine trees
on Mount Huang?
Yes, exactly.
I got it from the Literary Association.
Over these years,
new pine woods have been discovered,
in which the pine trees are old and solid.
Look.
Jinhe,
you want to enter the mountain?
No, I disagree.
Listen,
Jingdong is making a fuss.
Are you joining him now?
Rujun,
Jingdong is a bit stubborn,
but some of what he said is true.
If we give up
on the upcoming Tribute Ink selection,
there will probably be no place
for Li Ink in Huizhou
in the future.
I just checked the ledgers
at the ink workshop.
Ten years of heavy taxes have almost
emptied Li Ink's century-old savings.
Business is getting worse day by day.
At this rate, even if we make it through
this outbreak of pine wilt disease,
who knows
if we can make it
to the next Tribute Ink selection.
Rujun,
Li Ink might not have another chance.
Please allow me to go find
pine wood in the mountain.
Rujun!
Miss Li, we're getting off work.
Nice work today.
Get some rest then.
Sure.
We're closed for today.
Please come...
Young Lady, are you even going to
turn me away?
Sixth Grandfather,
what brings you here?
Good for you.
You've really started
your own ink workshop.
It must be no easy job.
Now that you're here, Sixth Grandfather,
please sit down for a cup of tea.
Today, I came here...
to ask you a favor.
Take a seat first.
Sure.
Speak your mind then.
There's an outbreak of pine wilt disease,
yet Li Ink needs pine wood
for the Tribute Ink selection.
In a few days,
I'll go to Mount Huang for pine wood.
I'd like you to come back
and manage the Li Ink workshop.